An underground passage?
Are you sure there even is one?
It's got to be there somewhere.
Well then, what do you need me to do?
Move the rubble.
What?
Use a gnome to find the passage
buried beneath all the debris.
W-Wait just a minute.
I can alter stone, as I did in Sungard,
but summoning a gnome for long periods
uses tremendous magic power.
And you expect me to use it to find a path
that may or may not exist under all that?!
Exactly.
You haven't the faintest idea
where this passage is, do you?
I'll burn through my magic in no time.
Magic power can be replenished!
Go on! Use as many as you need!
Kyle, do you have any idea
what using one of those is like?
Yeah. They're extremely effective.
And they taste terrible!
I'm begging you. There's no time.
While we're standing around arguing,
Gazus could be in danger.
Urza...
Please, Urza! You're the
only one who can do this!
You can do it! You can do
anything you put your mind to!
Please, Urza!
Oh, fine!
If that's what you want, I'll do it!
Now we just pin our hopes on her.
If you find that holy sword,
be sure to grab it for me!
Theron, you're certain the
demon you saw was a guy?
I only caught a glimpse through
the window, but yeah.
You saw a woman, right?
Yeah.
Which means there are at least
two demons in Karan right now.
Two demons...
Yuck.
I feel sick.
Wait a minute.
What's this?
Hey, Kyle!
Did you find something?
This has got to be it—
The hidden underground passage!
Stay on your guard.
Those demons might be up ahead.
Demons, huh?
That was my first time seeing one,
but he seemed real dangerous.
Like my mom when she fights all out.
Individual demons are superior
in combat compared to humans.
You're not wrong to regard them
as monsters like her.
I'm going to tell Miss Layla
what you said about her!
You're quite knowledgeable about demons, Kyle.
They warrant that much caution.
They're dangerous.
With the shape Urza's in, the two
of you shouldn't go any farther.
What?! Surely you're not
telling us to turn back now!
We've come this far!
We're staying with you until the end!
It'll be fine.
Theron's here this time.
Worst case, even if he shows up,
I should be able to protect them.
Kyle, look!
No way. Is this...
It's too similar.
What's all this?
A forbidden rite.
Though, from the look of it,
the scale and formula are simple enough.
What's this about it being forbidden?
It's a ritual to convert the life energy
of a sacrifice into magic power.
These clothes...
This is the governor's aide
we met the other day!
Then those must be the
kidnapped people of Karan.
In other words, someone needed
sacrifices for some powerful magic,
so they resorted to kidnapping residents?
That's what it looks like.
I see, I see...
They're focusing on quality over quantity.
This magic circle slowly squeezes
the life out of each victim.
But with this meager catalyst...
It will soon exceed its capacity
for magic power and blow.
Are you saying it'll explode?
Indeed. And with that much magic,
it could wipe half the city off the map.
That would be a catastrophe!
So, what kind of spell
are they trying to cast here?
I can't be certain, but...
I sense someone approaching.
Looks like it's done.
Would it hurt you to say anything?
Does our current situation displease you so?
Working with a human collaborator
to gather intel peacefully...
I thought you were on board with the plan.
How is this peaceful?
This was the human's idea.
They can be so barbaric.
I'm talking about you killing
the humanoids at the embassy.
Was that really necessary?
That was also our collaborator's request.
How could I refuse?
I feel I've followed our order
about minimizing casualties, though.
We were also ordered
not to attract attention.
That demon...
Again, it was our collaborator's request.
He said to make a scene, since he
was staging an abduction elsewhere.
Even so!
More importantly, have you forgotten?
About the item our king desires.
It still irritates me to be
working with a mere human.
We must cooperate with him to get it.
This, too, shows our loyalty to our liege!
All we do is for the demon king.
The demon king?
Now then, I've finished cleaning up the trash.
This is one depressing hole.
I'm going to get some fresh air.
We managed not to get caught.
That was incredibly tense.
They sounded so stuck-up.
Even if they weren't demons,
we'd never be friends.
Minimizing casualties, eh?
I've heard the current demon king
is quite moderate, but how strange.
Well, thanks to this,
we've gotten some good intel.
Now...
We just have to find Governor Bax and Gazus.
What is this place?
Kyle!
Is that... Gazus?!
Thank goodness! He's alive!
Who are you people?!
Are you... Governor Bax?
That's right.
What are you doing here?
You refused to see us because you were ill.
I see. It's you lot!
You're the messengers from Zirgus.
The empire invaded us
and Zirgus tried to control us,
but you won't get your way with our city!
I will protect Karan!
Protect it? What are you talking about?
You're kidnapping residents
and sacrificing them.
Why would you do that?
For Karan...
To protect Karan!
Protect Karan?
Is something going to happen to it?
Karan's ore veins will soon be depleted.
Gazus, don't!
You would still defy me?!
Sir, there's no hiding it anymore.
It's time to reveal the truth.
The ore veins?
Karan's lifeblood.
I suppose they wouldn't last
a whole millennium.
Once the veins are depleted,
Karan will have nothing.
Jobs will dry up. Our skilled smiths
will scatter to the winds.
Zirgus's control will grow stronger,
and we'll lose our autonomy.
The empire might even invade again!
Shut up! I won't let that happen!
We must reclaim our former glory!
I'll do whatever it takes!
At this rate, Karan is done for!
You were afraid of that.
You wanted to reclaim our glory.
You said it would require some sacrifices.
The sacrifices are a trivial problem.
No, they're not even a problem at all!
You're terminally ill, aren't you?
I'd wager you only have a month left.
So he really is sick.
The demons took advantage
of his vulnerability.
How very rude of you.
I'd rather you not accuse us
of taking advantage of anyone.
We simply offered him a deal.
Miranda! You're awake.
G-Goh...
I-I...
It's all right.
I'm sure Kyle's party will find Dad.
A deal?
What do you mean?
I have no reason to tell you, but so be it.
This place was originally created
when the ore veins were consolidated.
And more could be gathered
with the same magic.
I see. So that's what the
forbidden rite is for.
Correct!
Hence why we made a deal.
In that case, you must've
asked something in return.
What are you after?
Why, the sword, of course.
It was used to defeat the previous demon king.
I've heard it's known among you
humanoids as the Holy Sword Rand.
Our sovereign wants it.
The Holy Sword Rand is here?!
You even know about that?
Originally, my mission was
to gather information on humanoids.
What are you investigating
besides the holy sword?
Humanity's forces. Beginning with Karan,
which produces untold weapons
used to make demons suffer.
In my reconnaissance, I learned of
Karan's situation and the governor's worries,
so I came along with a proposition.
It was two birds with one stone!
Th-That's what you were up to all along?!
You dastardly fiend!
Don't you think you've said too much?
Won't spill any more, huh?
No matter.
I'll take you on!
Oh? You've suddenly grown emboldened.
Or perhaps desperate.
I was just letting you carry on.
Both humanoids and demons get loose lips
when they think they have the upper hand.
Th-That was merely a farewell gift!
Don't get ahead of yourself, human!
Wait.
We must avoid as much fighting as possible.
Now that they've learned of our
existence, they must be silenced.
Our mission ends here.
Let's finish them off quickly and be gone!
Wh-What?
What about the sword?
Th-That's right.
What about the holy sword?
Don't you want it?!
Are you all right?
You can't leave now.
What will happen to Karan?!
You're still going on about that?
Do you really think demons would honor
any deal they made with humans?
How dare you.
If not for this trouble, we would've used
the earth-shifting magic as promised.
That catalyst is already at its limit.
They can't control it.
Wh-What?!
You're quite knowledgeable.
Well, even if the magic goes wild
and wipes out the city,
that's hardly our problem.
You bastard!
Why don't you take a nap?
You take the two girls.
But we're to refrain from killing humans!
It would seem they want a fight.
Look after him.
Yeah, you got it.
This shower of sparks must be dealt with!
Theron, stick with those two.
Sorry. I'm curious about something.
I'll be doing my own thing.
Huh? What're you talking about?
Fine. I'll figure it out, then.
I'll finish this guy quick.
Very well.
If you're so insistent, I'll play with you!
Flee this place at once.
I won't pursue you.
You think we'd fall for such an obvious trap?
A trap?
Why would I need to lay a trap?
You cannot so much as lay a finger on me.
I'm allowing you to escape. Now go.
You can't expect us to take that lying down!
Here I come!
Fools.
Liese!
You can't afford to take your eyes off me!
Salamander!
Demons are certainly impressive.
Her physical abilities are on another level.
She can see everything they're about to do.
I can tell how this will end.
You're not going to help?
Nah. She doesn't intend to kill them,
and she's not even going all out.
This is a perfect first fight against demons.
Indeed, it seems that way.
More importantly, Sildonia,
do you know what this is?
What is it?
I borrowed it from the governor.
You've got some sticky fingers.
I see.
This is a special magic item.
It conceals both a linked item
and its magic power.
I thought so.
In other words, there's something nearby
that he doesn't want us finding.
When the holy sword came up earlier,
the governor glanced in a certain direction.
You have sticky fingers and keen eyes, I see.
But your theory may be on the mark.
Here we are.
What happened to all your bravado?
He's got as much magic power as they say.
And his ability to cast
without incantations is a pain.
Just how many can he fire in a row?!
I can't even get close to him!
Take this!
A marvelous scream.
It's time to end this!
I'll leave your head
so you may have a proper burial.
No doubt about it. This is it!
I found the holy sword!
Next Time
Duel
Next time: "Duel."